Guide to the Barbara Howes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1929-1991; Series I; 13.67; (14 boxes)
  - "Storm Warning," typescript draft, undated (Box 8)
  - "Copies of Poems," miscellaneous copies of printed poems, undated (Box 8)
  - "Published poems and prose, 1941-1961," binder scrabook of clippings of published works (Box 8)
  - "Published poems and prose, 1961-1972," binder scrapbook of clippings of published works (Box 8)
  - "Published poems and prose 1973--" binder scrapbook of clippings of published works, 1973-1980 (Box 8)
  - "Short Story Copies" (mislabeled binder), binder containing lists of poems sent out (1940s-1980s), with poetry typescripts and autograph manuscript notes on poetry, undated (Box 8)
  - Lists of letters, poetry worksheets, and correspondence, undated (Box 9)
    Includes correspondence from Gil Williams and Fred Chappell.
  - "Articles, Thesis, Ideas," typescript articles, undated (Box 9)
    Includes "Little Magazines," "B. Traven" (with correspondence), "Detective Fiction" (with correspondence), and notes for these articles and others
  - "Original Spanish Texts," photocopies of Spanish stories for anthologies, undated (Box 9)
  - Translations of Francois Villon's poetry, with notes, undated (Box 9)
  - Eye of the Heart, introduction, notes, and biographies, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Eye of the Heart, "Extra or rejected Stories," typescripts, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Fersen, Nicholas: translations, undated (Box 9)
  - Fersen, Nicholas: poems and letters, undated (Box 9)
  - "Hungarian Enterprise," poems and correspondence for magazine, undated (Box 9)
    Includes correspondence from Stephen Sandy (poem and note), correspondence and corrected poetry translations of various Hungarian writers, and Howes' retained copies of letters.
  - Eye of the Heart, translator notes and correspondence, [1973] (Box 9)
    Includes correspondence from: Ben Belitt (card); Lino Novas Calvo; William Grossman; Joan Daves; Alastair Reid (TPC, TLS); Ellie Randall; George Schack; Hardie St Martin; Edwin Honig; Leonard Mades; Susana Rudge; Carl Brandt; Arturo Uslar Pietri; Angel T. (Montevideo); Paul Bowles (TLS); S. Jill Levine
  - "Governor Philip H. Hoff,'' first draft of Sterling Memorial Lecture given at Williams College, typescript (carbon), corrected, 1962 (Box 9)
  - " Chimera reprint plan," correspondence with Kraus Reprints, undated (Box 9)
  - Eye of the Heart, rough drafts, undated (Box 9)
    Includes "Why Reeds Are Hollow," (by Gabriela Mistral, tr. William Jay Smith, heavily hand-corrected typescript); "Fear," (by Rene Marquis, typescript); "Concerning Senor de la Pera," (by Eliseo Diego, corrected typescript); "A Close Shave," (by Hernando Tellez, tr. Edouard Roditi, typescript with hand corrections); plus correspondence with Olga Mandell (sp?) (several TLS); plus misc. clean drafts, Juan Bosch, et al.
  - " Chimera Wind-Up," correspondence with Donald Gallup regarding donation of Chimera Archive to Yale, undated (Box 9)
  - "Nerval translations and plans," typescript copies of translations of Gerard de Nerval's poetry by Howes, undated (Box 9)
    Also includes correspondence with Teo Savory of Unicorn Press.
  - Eye of the Heart, lists and notes, undated (Box 9)
  - Christmas poems, 1956-1986; 2 (Box 9)
    Contains poems and broadsides from various years, plus invitation to John F. Kennedy's Inauguration, reading announcements and clippings about Howes.
    Includes: "Otis" (1968); "Talking to Animals" (1969, inscribed); "Regina Coeli" (1972, inscribed); "Wild Geese Flying'' (1966, inscribed); "Evening: Crown Point" (1971); "Returning to Stone Bay" (1970, inscribed); "Two poems" (1962); "Lignum Vitae" (1958, inscribed by Barbara and Bill); "Elm-Burning" (1967, several copies including proof sheet); "Montserrat: A Watercolor" (1984); "A Christmas Poem" (1978); "Sitting Around Traveling" (1980); "At Pigeon Point, Tobago" (1986); "Chimera"; ''The Field of the Cloth of Gold" (for John Lennon); "Sitting Around Travelling" (two versions); "Christmas Poem" (1974); "Christmas Poem" (1978); "Millefleur"; "Being Me" (several copies including proof sheet); "Christmas Poem" (1977); "Winter Morning" by William Jay Smith ( 1967, inscribed by William and Sonja); "Christmas Poem" ( 1964); "Harlem Brook'' by Richard Wilbur (Christmas, 1982, inscribed); "Early Supper" (1956, inscribed by Howes & WJS); "A Minor Ode to the Morgan House" by William Jay Smith (1961, inscribed by Howes & WJS); "Quail in Autumn" by William Jay Smith (1965, inscribed); "Leaning into Light" (1965, inscribed); plus a Christmas card from Kathleen MacArthur.
  - Poems and short stories, typescripts, undated; 2 (Box 9)
    Includes "The Road Commissioner" and "Force of Nature."
  - Eye of the Heart, reviews, 1973 (Box 9)
  - In the Cold Country, publication announcements, 1954 (Box 9)
  - "The Journey" by Ned O'Gorman (typescript inscribed to Howes), undated (Box 9)
  - The Blue Garden, galleys, undated (Box 9)
  - Lists of poems sent out, 1939-1941; 2 (Box 9)
  - Looking up at Leaves, bound galley proofs, 1966 (Box 9)
  - "Translations," poetry typescripts and worksheets, undated (Box 9)
  - "Family History," autograph manuscript notes, undated (Box 9)
  - "Current Work - Critical Articles," loose notes, worksheets, and typescripts, undated (Box 9)
  - List of poems, 1960-1970 (Box 9)
  - The Blue Garden, typescript in binder, 1972 (Box 9)
  - "New Poems," typescript with corrections in binder, undated (Box 10)
  - Looking up at Leaves, new poems, typescripts, corrected, [1966] (Box 10)
  - Suppertime Tales, and The Road Commissioner and Other Stories, typescripts, [1983] (Box 10)
  - Journals and diaries, undated; 4 (Box 10)
  - The Eye of the Heart, proof copy, 1973 (Box 10)
  - "Barbara Howes' Poems," tribute to Howes at the Academy of American Poets with programs, correspondence and poetry, undated (Box 10)
  - Collected Poems, 1945-1990, typescript (Box 10)
  - "The Blueberry Barrens: Collected Poems," typescript, [1990] (Box 10)
  - Christmas poems, 1948-1993; 21 (Box 11)
    Includes: "Otis" (1968); "Talking to Animals" (1969); "Regina Coeli" (1972); "Wild Geese Flying" (1966); "Evening: Crown Point" (1971); "The Sixth Color of the Afternoon"; "Hubert Walking-A Profile" (broadside); "For Mother: A Log" (for her 80th birthday 2/11/68); "A Liking for People and Animals" (Homage to Helen, broadside, 1968); "Returning to Stone Bay" (1970); "A Christmas Poem: A Parable (1975); "Looking up at Leaves" (1963); "Two poems" (1962); ''The Snow Hole" (1960); "Lignum Vitae" (1958); "Elm-Burning" (1967); "Two Poems" (Howes & William Jay Smith, 1948); "Old Man on the Isthmus" (1957, WJS); "A Christmas Poem" (1978); "Sitting Around Traveling" (1980); "A Christmas Poem: A Point of View" (for Cary, 1977); "An Epithalamium" (for Petie and Frank Palmer, 21 June 1964); ''To W.H. Auden on his 50th Birthday'' (1957); "For Helen and Bob Allen" (May 16, 1970); "Early Supper" (1956); "A Christmas Poem: Man with Violin" (1976); "Christmas Poems'' (1973); "Christmas Poems" (1974); "Millefleurs" (two different printings); "Being Me" (broadside); "Christmas Poem" (1964); "A Minor Ode to the Morgan Horse" by William Jay Smith (1961, inscribed); "Leaning into Light" (1965); ''The Triumph of Love" (Caliban Press, 1953, 1/150, signed); "The Bead Curtain" by William Jay Smith (to W. H. Auden on his 50th Birthday, 1957, 1/100, signed); "Snow" by William Jay Smith (broadside, 1953); "Two French Poems" (by Howes & WJS, 1950); publication announcement for Howes' first book ''The Undersea Farmer" (1948); "Typewriter Birds" by William Jay Smith (1954, inscribed); ''The Stork" (announcement of Greg's birth, 9121/54); "Christmas poems" (1984-88, multiple copies); "Chimera" (1994, inscribed); "We are born ... " (1979); "A Christmas Poem" (1975); "A Vital Day'' (1993); "Color of Day'' (1992); ''Two Poems" by William Jay Smith (1959); "Wonders" (1979) and "Turtle" by David Smith (undated)
  - "The Time of My Life" (i.e. Collected Poems ): drafts, notes and related material, [1990]; 12 (Box 12)
  - Photocopies of works published by Barbara Howes, 1958-1979 (Box 12)
    Includes "The Baroness Entertains" (on Isak Dinesen, 1958); "Ann Stafford and Barbara Howes" (introduction to reading by Robert Phillips, 1979); "Interview" (with Howes, undated); "Voice of America" piece (1963)
  - "Reviews of out-of-print Treasures project," correspondence and typescripts about obscure and/or overlooked books, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - "The Field of the Cloth of Gold": autograph manuscript drafts, variant typescripts of this poem honoring John Lennon, including retained copy of Howes' letter to Yoko Ono, 1981 (Box 12)
  - "A Report on Experience as Fulbright-Hays Lecturer" by William Jay Smith (photocopy), 1981 (Box 12)
  - Lists of poems from readings, presentations, Christmas poems, undated (Box 12)
  - "Pergolesi's Dog, etc." correspondence with Guy Davenport and a copy of his essay, 1980 (Box 12)
  - "Writings - Reviews, Odds and Ends 1960-," literary reviews by Howes, typescripts, autograph notes, clippings (Box 12)
    Includes Howes' writings or reviews of Emily Grosholz; Robert A. Wilson; Stanley Hyman; Beatriz Guido; William Troy; Andrew Lang; Marianne Moore; Sylvia Plath; Glenway Wescott; Derek Walcott; Judith Wright, Anne Sexton; etc.
  - "Jokes and Japes - Descriptions Illuminating Commentary", 1948-1977 (Box 12)
    Includes correspondence from Howes to her mother (1948); Kim Cushman (1977) and Meryle Secrest (1977).
  - "Good poems - found", 1966-1980 (Box 12)
    Original poems include: Gene Baro: "Country Water" (typewritten poem, signed and dated 5/31/63); Kim Cushman: "Greater Play'' (with cover letter, 1980); Robert Phillips: "Academy Terrace Party: A Pantoum" (inscribed); "Poem for Christmas 1980" (signed poem card); "Flatworms" (original typed poem, inscribed); William Meredith "In the Rif Mountains" (inscribed, 1980); Lewis Turco: "Prothalamion" (signed poem card, 1980); "The Covered Bridge" (signed poem card, 1979); Margot Archer: "The Camels" (signed poem card); Stephen Sandy: "Air for Air" (signed poem card); Arthur Gregor ''The Link'' (signed poem card); Norma Farber "Late Evening in Autumn" (original typed poem, inscribed, 1979); Norman Campbell Cross (original carbon manuscript, stapled and inscribed, 1970); Roy Basler "A Poodle Killed in the Street" (inscribed tearsheet); Ned O'Gorman "Color" (signed); "Bach" (signed); Lawrence Lieberman: "Santena" (inscribed tearsheet, 1966); plus various poems by Robert Phillips, Derek Walcott; Seamus Heany; Jorge Luis Borges; W. S. Merwin; Ned O'Gorman; and many others.
  - "Literary Business - Translation", 1961-1977 (Box 12)
    Translations of Nerval (numerous drafts and worksheets), Theophile Gautier, plus significant Literary correspondence.
    Includes correspondence from: Norman Thomas di Giovanni; Jean Garrigue; Elizabeth Kray; William Jay Smith; Kenneth F. Canfield; Nicky Mariano (holograph Lorca translation with letter).
  - " Light and Dark: A Volume of Poems Written by Barbara Howes" by Dorothy Nichol (thesis), plus misc. student and fan correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 13)
  - "W.J.S.-Things of interest," signed poems and correspondence, 1965-1974 (Box 13)
    Includes "On the Edge" (inscribed poem); "At Delphi" (for Allen Tate) (typescript dated 11/19/74); "At Delphi" (folded broadside inscribed to Howes with letter); "Journey to the Dead Sea" (inscribed to Howes); letters; "June '68" by Andrei Voznesensky (tr. by WJS, inscribed to Howes); "Winter Morning" (signed poem); "A Tribute to William Jay Smith" by Frank MacShane (1967); "A Rose for Katharine Anne Porter" (signed poem, 1965); "A Vermonter's March" (newspaper article by WJS); plus one letter from Sonja Smith (undated)
  - The Sea-Green Horse: master set of galleys with corrections, 1970 (Box 13)
  - The Sea-Green Horse: master set of galleys/page proofs, 1970 (Box 13)
  - The Sea-Green Horse: original manuscript paste-ups with cover letter from Macmillan, 1970; 3 (Box 13)
  - "Green": inscribed copy of this William Jay Smith broadside, 1980 (Box 13)
  - ''Ahoy!'' broadside, signed (Box 14)
  - Bennington Poems, late 1930s; 2 (Box 14)
    Early poems from Bennington College in leather case with notes.
    Includes notes and and original programs of the proceedings of Carl Jung's Eranos Conference from 1938.
  - Light and Dark: first page proofs, 1959 (Box 14)
- Correspondence, 1922-1995; Series II; 5; (5 boxes)
  Contains incoming letters and retained copies of outgoing letters. The categories "Literary Correspondence," "Family Correspondence," "Political Correspondence" and "Business Correspondence" were devised by the dealer and have been retained, although there appears to be considerable overlap in some cases. Folder titles are largely transcribed from existing folders or from appraisal or dealer descriptions.
  Howes' correspondence with other authors, particularly American poets, was extensive, and correspondents include Leonie Adams, Elizabeth Bishop, Malcolm Cowley, Denise Levertov, James Merrill, W. S. Merwin, Katherine Anne Porter, Theodore Roethke, and Richard Wilbur. Family correspondence, particularly Howes' lengthy series of letters to her mother, documents Howes' personal and professional life and travels, while other files document her poetry readings, lectures, and other public appearances.
  - Literary correspondence, late 1930s (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence from Charlee Wilbur (wife of Richard Wilbur), Katherine MacArthur (Australian), Rose Goldman, Robert Brooks, Honora Gifford, Warren Sung (Chinese poet), Walter Martin (bookseller), W. S. Merwin, Joseph Paresi, Anthony Hecht, Jacques Barzun; Denise Levertov, Josephine Jacobsen, Elizabeth Coleman (president of Bennington College), Harold Acton, Lady Troubridge, Elizabeth Marangoni, Sam Hunter, William Maguire, Dana Gioia, Edouard Roditi, Robert Phillips, Fred Chappell, Wallace Fowlie, Robert Wilson (bookseller), Robert Shaw, Molyneux (designer), Nicky Mariano (Bernard Berenson's partner), Toto von Koopmann (Dutch spy).
  - "Correspondence to Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith," Literary correspondence, 1948-1995; 2 (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence from Leonie Adams, Dore Ashton, W. H. Auden, Gene Baro, Jacques Barzun, Cary F. Baynes, Elizabeth Bishop, Louise Bogan, Juan Bosch, Kenneth Burke, Kenneth Clark, Cecil Collins, Malcolm Cowley, Hubert Creekmore, Caresse Crosby, Dana Gioia, Peggy Guggenheim, Anthony Hecht, Sam Hunter, Josephine Jacobsen, Carolyn Kizer, Oskar Kokoschka, Denise Levertov, Robert Lowell, James Merrill, John Robinson, W. S. Merwin, Marianne Moore, Howard Nemerov, Walker Percy, Katherine Anne Porter, Kathleen Raine, Alastair Reid, Beatrice Roethke, Theodore Roethke, Gary Soto, May Swenson, Allen Tate, Dylan Thomas, Eudora Welty, Richard Wilbur, Adja Yunkers.
  - Correspondence to Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith, 1947-1986; 48 (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence from Leonie Adams, Jorge Amado, Dore Ashton, Jacques Barzun, Bernard Berenson, Elizabeth Bishop, R. P. Blackmur, Louise Bogan, Juan Bosch, Paul Bowles, Cleanth Brooks, Witter Bynner, Hayden Carruth, Eleanor Clark, Tristam Coffin, Padraic Colum, Malcolm Cowley, Hubert Creekmore, J. V. Cunningham, Harriet DeOnis, Babette Deutsch, Richard Eberhart, Dudley Fitts, George Garrett, Jorge Guillen, Donald Hall, Seamus Heaney, John Holmes, C. Gabrera Infante, Josephine Jacobsen, Alfred Kazin, X. J. Kennedy, Carolyn Kizer, Oskar Kokoschka, Olga Kokoschka, Stanley Kunitz, James Laughin, Denise Levertov, Frank MacShane (biographer), James Merrill, W. S. Merwin, Czeslaw Milosz, Marianne Moore, Pablo Neruda, John Frederick Nims, Ned O'Gorman, Octavio Paz, Norman Holmes Pearson, Walker Percy, Robert Phillips, Katherine Anne Porter, Edouard Roditi, Beatrice Roethke, Theodore Roethke, Stephen Spender, Enid Starkie, Allen Tate, Isabella Gardner Tate, Cesar Vallejo, Robert Penn Warren, Eudora Welty, John Hall Wheelock, Richard Wilbur, Adja Yunkers.
  - "Replies to Letters," Political correspondence, 1967-1978 (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence from Senator Patrick Leahy, Governor Phllip H. Hoff, J. W. Fulbright, Don Edwards, Edmund Muskie, Roger Mudd, George P. Aiken, Joseph D. Tydings, Winston Prouty, Allard K. Lowenstein, Mark O. Hatfield, Paul H. Douglas, Chartes E. Goodell, Fred R. Harris, Harold Levy, William Proxmire, Walter F. Mondale, Frank Church, Bryan Rustin, Eugene J. McCarthy, James Oakes, Birch Bayh, Max Frankel, Robert T. Stafford, Silvio O. Conte, Ralph W. Yarborough, John McGiennon, Jacques H. Leroy, Frank E. Moss, Morris K. Udall, James Reston.
  - Literary correspondence, 4 (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence from Dana Gioia, Isabel Bolton/Mary Britton Miller, Kathleen Raine, William Maxwell, Elizabeth Hardwick, Judith Wright, William Meredith, Elsa Gress, Vivian Mercier, Marcus Cunliffe, Kenneth Burke, Granville Hicks, Alan Cheuse, Paul Mellon, Clement Richer, Florette Morand, Alain Bosquet, Helen Thurber, Arthur Gregor, Alaslair Reid, Francis Ferguson, Peter Davison, William Stafford, Herbert Cahoon, Vassar Miller, Galen Williams, John Mclennan, Marjorie Benchley (wife of Nathaniel), Bernard Weinbaum, Alida Monro, Norman Campbell Cross, Tony Ostroff, Sheelagh Burns, Tom Bewing, Robert Phillips, G. S. Fraser, Ned O'Gorman, Kathleen MacArthur, Rupert S. Holland, Alicia Reyes, James Ramsey Ullman, William Maguire, Marjorie Ferguson, Rex Warner, Cecily Mackworth, Jack Sweeney, Robert Fitzgerald, Paul Brickhill, Peter Taylor, Jean F. Briere (Ambassador of Haiti), Arthur Gregor, Peter Blume, Nicholas Fersen, Martin Hall, Rose Goldman, Marguerite Mespoulet, Harriott Allen, Gretchen Waldo, George Palmer (New York Times), Gilbert Harrison, Bernard McCabe, Jeffrey Miller, Peter Kaplan, Thekla Clark, Connie Carrier, Cary Baynes, Norman C. Cross, Warren Cook, Nathan Wilbur, Robert Elman, Austin Clarke, Katherine Biddle, John Hearne; A. R. Ammons, Cleanth Brooks, Henry Taylor, Aldo Capasso, Robert Wilson, Frank Glazer, Barney Rossell, Donald Gallup, Charles Guenther, Harriet Woods, Ben Belitt, Gene Baro, Frederick Beuchner, Milton Saul, Marie Bullock, Wallace Fowlie, H. L. Mitchell (Southern Tenant Farmer's Union).
  - Family correspondence, 1922-1951 (Box 15)
    Letters written by Barbara Howes to her mother over a long period of years (1922-1951), ranging over many topics and locations, describing both her work and who she met during her travels.
    Included in the letters are accounts of meeting such individuals as Dylan Thomas, T. S. Eliot, Enid Starkie, Stephen Spender, Olivia Manning, Simone de Beauvior, Caresse Crosby, Harold Acton, Bernard Berenson, Graham Greene, Tennessee Williams and Truman Capote.
  - Cary F. Baynes / Ximena de Angulo, correspondence re: Jungian studies, undated (Box 15)
    Note: Ximena was a college friend of Barbara Howes from Bennington College (and coeditor of Chimera magazine) and remained a close friend throughout their lives. Cary F. Baynes, Ximena's mother, worked with Dr. Carl Jung and introduced Howes to the Jungs. Barbara attended several tagungs at the Eranos Conferences in Geneva and spent weekends with the Jungs in Ascona.
  - William Jay Smith correspondence, 1947 (Box 15)
    Letters from William Jay Smith to Howes written while we was at Oxford describing the situation there and the various people he encountered.
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence from Sheelagh Bums, Jack Murphy, John Malcolm Brinnin, Marguerite Mespoulet, Harvey Simmons, Roloff Beny (protege of Peggy Guggenheim), Rose Goldman, Marjorie Ferguson, Charles Abbott, Toto von Koopman, Jane Sabersky.
  - University of Vermont Special Collections, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Literary business correspondence, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Retained copies of outgoing letters, "To Be Xeroxed" (Box 15)
  - "Marika, JHW letters about appendix to Guilman Family book" (Box 15)
  - Wilbur, Charlee (Box 15)
  - Wilson, Robert A. (Box 15)
  - Literary correspondence (Box 16)
    Includes correspondence from Dore Ashton, William Meredith, Jacques Barzun, Vassar Miller, Donald Hall, Robert Phillips, Harry Duncan, Claude Fredericks, Radcliffe Squires, Florette Morand, Robert Wilson, Frank MacShane, Josephine Jacobsen, Carolyn Kizer, Dana Gioia, Eleanor Clark, Senator Patrick Leahy, Glyn Coffins, James Merrill, Camille Paglia.
  - "Help from friends," correspondence from friends regarding financial assistance, undated (Box 16)
  - Literary corespondence, undated (Box 16)
    Includes correspondence from Chartes Guenther, Fred Chappel, Hugh Miller and many others.
  - Notes from publishers, undated (Box 16)
  - Literary correspondence (Box 16)
    Includes correspondence from Lewis Turco, Doris Holmes (wife of John Holmes), Margaret Marshall, Shirley Komrower, Elizabeth Kray, Honora Gifford, Ned O'Gorman, Robert Phillips, Edouard Roditi, Fred Chappell, Victor Howes, Peter Blume, Nona Balakian, Indrek Tart (Estonian poet), Judith Wright, Charles Guenther (with photo), Miller Williams, Charlee Wilbur, Wallace Fowlie, Seymour Lawrence (publisher), Betty Eberhart, Daniel Halpern, Lysander Kemp, Gil Williams, Kathleen MacArthur, William Jay Smith.
  - "Literary Business 1988" (Box 16)
    Includes letter from the Schaffner Agency, Royalty statements from "The Eye of the Heart" anthology, letter from Howes to agent Timothy Schaffner, letter from Thomas Underwood, (biographer of Allen Tate), letter from Albert Newgarden.
  - "Letters to cousins, 1988" (Box 16)
    Includes copies of letters from Howes, plus one to Dana and Mary Gioia, all signed, mostly concerning stay of three days in hospital with details about Pownal and work.
  - Hauschka, Elsa Voorhees correspondence, undated (Box 16)
    Copy of Barbara Howes' reply to Elsa Voorhees Hauschka (composer) with thoughts about music and her way of composing
  - Trissel, James, 1985 (Box 16)
    Letter from letterpress artist James Trissel about printing of broadside of "Looking Up at Leaves" for the Press at Colorado College for exhibit of 24 broadsides at the Fales Collection, Burst Library, May 9, 1985.
  - Levine, Suzanne Jill, undated (Box 16)
    Letter from Suzanne Jill Levine (translator) about an English reprinting of The Eye of the Heart.
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 16)
    Includes correspondence from Harry Duncan, Charles Wilbur, William Jay Smith, Albert Newgarden, Charles Guenther, Emily Grosholz, Frank MacShane and Stephen Sandy (with poem entitled "Picnic with Morgan").
  - Letters to friends, undated (Box 16)
    Includes copies of letter Barbara Howes wrote to Robert Phillips, William Jay Smith (concerning new book and David Smith), Frank MacShane, and Frank Glazer.
  - Smith, William Jay. Correspondence regarding the poems of Nina Cassian, undated (Box 16)
    Includes worksheets of translations of Barbara Howes (with help of Ken Cushman).
  - Elysian Press. Letters regarding Moving and sales accounts, undated (Box 16)
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 16)
  - "Letters from friends", undated (Box 16)
    Includes one letter from Frank MacShane and signed poem by Ned O'Gorman.
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 16)
    Includes letters from Edward Kamau Braithwaite and Dan Monte (sp?), plus correspondence about other readings and magazine submissions.
  - Political correspondence: Woods, Harriet: Lieutenant Governor of Missouri, undated (Box 16)
  - "Literary correspondence", [1987] (Box 16)
    One file of letters from Frank MacShane, Charles Guenther, Charlee Wilbur (long letter dated 6/1/1987 just after Richard Wilbur's appointment as Poet Laureate, plus a long letter from the Camargo Foundation about Wilbur).
  - Literary correspondence (Box 16)